I-Da Chiang

E-mail: idchiang@asiaa.sinica.edu.tw | LinkedIn: idchiang

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Dust Life Cycle & Interstellar Medium

I am interested in studying the evolution of interstellar dust with multiwavelength observations. One of my projects is measuring the spatially resolved dust-to-metals ratio in the nearby galaxies, and interpreting the results with dust chemical evolution models, simulations and ancillary data.

HI 21 cm Line & Radio Astronomy

The distribution of neutral gas is a key element in dust sciences and cold gas dynamics. The $\rm Hi~21~cm$ line traces neutral hydrogen atoms in the ISM. I reduced new $\rm Hi~21cm$ line data of $\sim \! \! 30$ galaxies observed by VLA with CASA. These new data allows us to construct a new dust-to-metals ratio survey in the nearby galaxies.

EMPLOYMENT

Institute of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Academia Sinica

2021 - Current

Postdoc Fellow

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2021

Graduate Research Assistant

- Built a python-based toolkit for dust SED fitting and multi-wavelength data analysis.
- Analyzed the dust-to-gas and dust-to-metal ratios in the spiral galaxy M101.
- Analyzed the dust-to-metal ratio and CO-to- H_2 conversion factor in detail in \sim 50 nearby galaxies.
- Examined the empirical radiation distribution law and the turbulent power spectrum in the local group galaxies with the dust SED fitting tools.
- Reduced HI 21cm line data of \sim 30 galaxies observed by VLA with the Common Astronomy Software Applications package (CASA).

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2016

Teaching Assistant (TA) and Lab TA Coordinator

- Familiarized new teaching assistants with lab setups and teaching skills.
- Led discussion sessions, which helped ~ 40 students each week.
- Led introductory level physics lab, with 24 students per session.
- Improved course materials from feedback from teaching assistants and students.

National Taiwan University

2012 - 2014

Graduate Research Assistant

- Improved the photo-degradation reactor for wastewater treatment with plasmonic nano-particles.
- Built the protocol for maintaining/using the sputter machine and clean room.

Taiwan (R.O.C.) Armed Forces

2011 - 2012

Second Lieutenant (Company second-in-command)

EDUCATION

University of California San Diego Ph.D. (Physics and Astronomy) Thesis: "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies" Adviser: Prof. Karin M. Sandstrom	2014 - 2021
National Taiwan University M.S. (Physics) Thesis: "Plasmonic Enhanced Optical Disk Reactor for Wastewater Treatment" Adviser: Prof. Din Ping Tsai	2012 - 2014
National Taiwan University B.S. (Physics)	2007 - 2011
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Lab TA Coordinator, PHYS 1-ABC Lab – UCSD	2015 - 2016
Teaching Assistant, PHYS 1-A Lab – UCSD	2014 - 2015

REFEREED PUBLICATIONS (AS FIRST OR SECOND AUTHOR)

- 4) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, E. Koch, K. Kreckel, A.K. Leroy, A. Schruba, D. Utomo, T. Williams, "Resolving the Dust-to-Metals Ratio and CO-to-H₂ Conversion Factor in the Nearby Universe", 2021, ApJ, 907, 29.
- 3) E.W. Koch, **I-D. Chiang**, D. Utomo, J. Chastenet, A.K. Leroy, E.W. Rosolowsky, K.M. Sandstrom, "Spatial power spectra of dust across the Local Group: No constraint on disc scale height", 2020, MN-RAS, 492, 2663.
- 2) D. Utomo, I-D. Chiang, A.K. Leroy, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, "The Resolved Distributions of Dust Mass and Temperature in Local Group Galaxies", 2019, ApJ, 874, 141.
- 1) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, L.C. Johnson, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, "The Spatially Resolved Dust-to-metals Ratio in M101", 2018, ApJ, 865, 117.

A full list of refereed publications at ADS Public Library is available here.

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

Lunch talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS		
	Colloquium , "Multiwavelength observations of dust, gas, and metals in the $z\sim 0$ universe", NCU, Taoyuan, Taiwan	2022
	Contributed talk, "Dust, gas, and metals: Observing Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies", Galaxy Evolution Workshop 2021, NAOJ, Tokyo, Japan	olu- 2021
	Colloquium , "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei wan	i, Tai- <i>2021</i>
	Contributed talk, "Dust, gas and metals: Resolving the Dust Life Cycle in the Nearby Universe", The 235th Meeting, Honolulu, USA	2020
	Special seminar, "Dust-to-Metals Relation in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Taiwan	2019
	Poster, ASROC2019, Taichung, Taiwan	2019
	Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Galaxies", Dusting Universe, Tucson, USA	the <i>2019</i>

2019

Tea time talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA	2018
Poster, CPHDUST, Copenhagen, Denmark	2018
Poster, ASROC2018, Kinmen, Taiwan	2018
Lunch talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA	2018
OUTREACH EXPERIENCE	
Student seminar @ ASIAA – lecturer	2021
Research in physics workshop for community college students @ UCSD – lecturer	2021
Python workshop for physics undergrads @ UCSD – presenter	2019
Life as a scientist @ Jianguo High School – lecturer	2019
STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights @ San Diego, USA – presenter	2018
Tech Trek @ UCSD – presenter	2017
Physics GRE bootcamp @ UCSD – teaching assistant	2016
AWARDS	
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2014
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2011
Presidential Award, National Taiwan University	2011